Gabriel Ramos

Rio de Janeiro, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil



gabriel.o.c.ramos@gmail.com



+5521983580220



linkedin.com/in/gabrielocramos

Summary

Technology is my big passion. This is how we can connect people around the world, from all classes and cultures, and make things faster and functional.

I've started coding when I was 11 y-o, doing my own simple HTML/CSS websites and trying to make it better every day. Then I discovered PHP existence and started doing my own CRUD system for my geek blog. (HTML / CSS / PHP / JavaScript)

At the University, while studying physics, I've been part of GFRJ (Rio de Janeiro Rocket Team), in which I worked at Payload team, working as coder and doing scientific experiments (like a Cosmic Ray Detector) for the rockets and co-working with Avionics team (rockets system). We got 1st place at a Brazilian Competition and 3rd at International (Spaceport America Cup), in Best Solid Motor Rocket category. (Python)

Since 2018 I started working as freelancer for many important projects of Companies through Inventa Produtos Digitais. Then, in 2021, I started working for Loomer Tech, in which I improved my mobile development skills and many projects for the Company and its clients, getting Scrum Master position in 4 months. (HTML / CSS / (Sass/SCSS) / PHP / JavaScript / C#.NET / React Native / Redux / WordPress / React.js / Next.js / API's / Scrum)

Then, in July 2021, I was hired by B2W Digital / Americanas S.A. as Software Developer, for Mobile Development with React Native, working directly with the international e-commerce team (Cross Border) in Soub! app development. (React Native / Redux / API's / Scrum)

Still growing up, improving my skills and getting better every day. Breaking my limits, achieving higher, going further.

Experience



Software Developer

americanas s.a.

Jul 2021 - Present (4 months +)

- App and Web Developer of the international e-commerce division.
- Developer of the new Soub! mobile app in React Native.
- Working with React Native for e-commerce app development.

loomer

Tech Manager

Loomer Tech

May 2021 - Jul 2021 (3 months)

- Responsible for a better Scrum Methodology use.
- The header of e-commerce integration of apps.
- Creator of better apps architecture.
- Made the new front-end layout of the Company apps that turned it more professional looking.

- Supervision and help for Junior and internship developers.
- · I helped the company achieve high goals and received bonuses with cash promotions and bigger participation.

Frontend Developer

Loomer Tech

Feb 2021 - May 2021 (4 months)

- RESTful APIs integrations.
- Responsible for the front-end work of all the company apps in React Native.
- Front-end developer of web based systems in React.js.
- Responsible for the company website UX development.
- Worked to solve complex problems using the latest in Cloud, Mobile, and Web Technologies.
- Worked well independently and on a team to solve problems.

IT Technical Mananger

Milk & Fruit

Jan 2019 - Jun 2021 (2 years 6 months)

- · Provided superior design skills and a strong understanding of computer software.
- Planned and developed written policies and procedures for computer operations.
- · Identified client needs and suggested appropriate services to enhance client experience.
- Helped to achieve a consistent look and visual theme across the website by promoting uniform fonts, formatting, images, and layout.
- Coordinated mailings, marketing materials, and website content.
- · Remained knowledgeable in new standards, technologies, and trends in website development.
- Managed the maintenance of machines.
- Performed scheduled updates, routine maintenance calls, and made repairs when necessary.

Front End Developer

Inventa Produtos Digitais

Dec 2018 - Jun 2021 (2 years 7 months)

- Freelancer developer since 2018 for the company, being completely hired in 2020.
- Full-stack development for web based .NET systems.
- Front-end developer of all mobile and web applications.
- Front-end developer of all websites.
- · Effectively translated client requirements into application designs and system requirements.
- Provided effective troubleshooting and remediation for web applications.
- Worked to solve complex problems using the latest in Cloud, Mobile, and Web Technologies.

· Successfully identified, diagnosed, and fixed website problems, including broken links, typographical errors, and formatting issues.

Astronomy Instructor

OBA! Planetário Itinerante

Aug 2017 - Aug 2020 (3 years 1 month)

- Attended workshops and classes to further my professional skills.
- Motivated students to learn and participate.
- Speeches all around the country about Astronomy and

Astrophysics in many universities, schools and scientific events.

Education



(\$) UERJ

Bacharelado e Licenciatura, Física 2016 - 2020

Centro Universitário UniCarioca

Bacharelado, Ciência da Computação 2017 - 2017

Colégio Apollo 12

Ensino Médio, Técnico em Eletrônica 2014 - 2015

Licenses & Certifications

- **Lean Six Sigma White Belt Certification** americanas s.a.
- Segurança da Informação americanas s.a.
- Lei Geral de Proteção de Dados (LGPD) americanas s.a.
- React Native The Practical Guide [2021 Edition] Udemy UC-51be0a9c-6404-4695-b5bc-84227a6a475a
- **Libras Programa Somar** americanas s.a.

Skills

Aplicativos móveis · Desenvolvimento web · JavaScript · Programação de computadores · Matemática Tecnologia da informação
React Native
CSS
HTML
Adobe Photoshop